good morning it is Tuesday April 14th
day a million of the pandemic I'm nearly
certain I am going live every morning at
8:30 a.m. except for when I'm grocery
shopping in which will be this Thursday
I am pretty sure tomorrow we are doing a
solution raising on I'd write down
remember resiliency efficiency and
fragility and I should be joined by Eric
and possibly Edward and whoever else
wants to join to discuss what we
currently do for those three things but
it currently looks like the resiliency
efficiency fragility trade-off and then
we're going to talk about what it looks
like in our version of an ideal future
and then we will be spending the
majority of the time the last 30 minutes
talking about what it could look like
what system what kind of solution could
we generate if we had 10,000 people and
$100,000 because that is what a solution
raising is we talked about what it looks
like what it could look like and what we
could do right now and that is what I'm
gonna do during this this hour if there
are people coming in to chat to and I
know it seems the extra queue this
morning yeah is to do that for my bigger
project the idea that with a tech slash
solutions solutions cooperative we can
create a world that works for everyone
and because everyone else shuts off hey
here's that sure what all the work so
everyone you know it's never existed
before in society isn't that I could
ever design a world that works for every
single human being it's that every
single human being is invited to come
and create a world that works for
themselves by creating solutions and
tools that would help them live their
best life help them live their life at
their highest level without dictating to
each other what that highest level could
or should be so right now in society to
me it looks like a very individualistic
society that you are thought to succeed
or fail on your own
merit one of the big issues being that
the merit most of the merit comes from
luck it comes from your genetic clock it
comes from your privilege it comes from
your circumstances and only a very
select minority of people are able to
succeed in this current society and then
we look at people who aren't succeeding
as failures people like you we don't
look at you like you weren't lucky
enough we look at you like you're not
determined enough you're not charismatic
enough there's something about you you
need to change in order to become a
success and as a society we're paying
the greatest price for that because
we're not getting people at their
highest self we're not getting their
works of art and inventions and
creativity and emotional support and all
the things we give much more easily when
we are supported supported by our
communities and each other and so is
that only what I wanted to say about
right now with the individuals the
perceived Tauber you'll be able to
succeed yeah
divide that part of what is done in this
and whether it's done intentionally or
not is that we are divided and so we're
much more easily to rule over when you
can point to the other and say that
they're the enemy as opposed to they
just happen to be different we have
different things to contribute if there
is a select minority of people that are
thought to be better because they worked
harder because they are more ingenious
because whatever the reason is that
they're part of that inner group and the
rest of us aren't quiet up to stuff it
costs all of us because it means what
you're trying to do is strive to become
part of that instead of striving to
become your version of your best self
which is the gonna be the point where
you can contribute the most to your own
life and society
so before I particularly repeat that
that portion of it I'll move on to what
the future could look like in my mind
the timeline once we actually start
creating technology that we own together
and improve together is five to ten
years
which is
way to suitable time line for a lot of
other people but I've seen how much
technology changes our lives in five to
ten years and that's without it being
ours that's with it being googles and
Facebooks and Microsoft's cetera etc and
Amazon I know we can recreate all of
those companies so that they're in the
benefit of humanity instead of in the
benefit of the shareholders of the
companies and even if we just did that
if we had just the level of technology
we currently have but we owned it
together so we can trust it and use it
that has a drastic impact on our lives
in society but I also know there are a
ton of tools we can create that they
would never create because it empowers
the masses because we need it to come
from the bottom in order for us to trust
it and be able to use it if they did it
we're not going to trust it they're
gonna be having an uphill battle that is
that the ready
so who does I get my I can't act axioms
confuse the sames but in the future if
we have a user tech cooperative a
solutions cooperative that we're all
owning together and we're all able to
offer our opinion on tools that need to
be created as well as what those tools
actually look like and we can more
easily trust and use those tools because
we can be as involved in the process as
we as we care to me that creates a whole
new world of possibility if we can if we
had the technology solutions because
they're generally technology solutions
that we come up with during the solution
raisings we've done seven of them so far
the eight point beam tomorrow and
they're not unfeasible we're gonna get
to in the next section but ten thousand
people and a hundred thousand dollars is
not a pie in the sky ideal version of
the future it's what we can create right
now if we had ten thousand people a
hundred thousand dollars and all of them
are powerful tools if we had right now
especially if we owned them together we
knew we can improve them together and we
knew we could trust them and they
interconnected with each other your food
at your food technology app that helps
you eat healthy and cheaper coordinate
with your neighbors can you know
communicate with your financial
which we haven't even done a solution
raising on finances but maybe it comes
up in efficiency and resiliency and
fragility tomorrow and then a week from
tomorrow we're doing one on I want to
say packaging then the week the
following Wednesday the 29th we're doing
one on the meta how is everything when
if you bring up education you're gonna
be talking about child care you're gonna
be talking about everything our cat
everything that that affects and so part
of the critique that I get is like well
you if you fix this you how do you it
has ripple effects on everything else
and that's why basically we need to
solve everything simultaneously and have
it feed back into the system because
nobody can plan out what a perfect
education system looks like well there
is no such thing but perfect education
system without it being in combination
with everything else in society so we're
doing like a meta solution raising a
what what is the interconnectedness of
the system what does it look like now
what could it look like in the future
and what could it look like for 10,000
people and $100,000 and so that is it
for the future a user cooperative that
is we own the technology is the future
which means we have as individuals the
tools to live our best lives not because
some of nificant being created them you
on musk isn't coming to save us he's
coming to save himself
Bill Gates isn't coming to save us he's
coming to save himself but we can save
ourselves we can be able to we can
create the solutions that we want to be
a part of not so that we can sell them
to the next group of people and become
millionaires and billionaires but so
that we can use the tools we can use the
tools to help us eat better we can use
the tools to have more of a say an
impact on our own healthcare or our have
efficient transportation whatever it is
that the project is focusing on if we
can create it for ourselves it's going
to concentrate on the purpose and not
the profit because we are actually
putting money in to create the solution
and so creating solutions that are
voluntary attractors that it's not about
creating a new elite
to impose their will on everyone else
the new 10,000 or the new 1% and they
get to run the new society it's about
creating a solution for those and with
those 10,000 people and then inviting
everybody else anyone who wants to be
part of that solution and so what we
could do right now if we had 10,000
people and $100,000 especially if those
10,000 people were willing to put in $10
a month then we have a hundred thousand
dollars per month to play to play with
with full transparency and
accountability to our membership who is
those 10,000 then we can create a
platform for collaboration what does a
social media platform look like that is
designed for massive collaboration that
you want to be a part of because there's
tons of people working on it but it's
their version of what collaboration
looks like and they're all missing
pieces and anything that is free to the
masses because we've paid for it as the
10,000 and for this particular project
the collaboration platform I think it
does need to be free so that it anyone
who wants to come and work on someone's
project wants to find out what is
available to work on what is available
to fund what level they can participate
at and give them feedback to future
iterations to constantly improve them
for their individual needs like the heat
I like it for these reasons I don't like
it for these reasons we find what's not
working and we continually improve it
with each iteration which is something
we can't do with other people's
technology which is why as much as I
keep hearing about discord it's not ours
it's not connected to Google and
Facebook which gives it a disadvantage
not an advantage and we can't improve it
together so even if it solves the need
it's not it doesn't it's like it doesn't
we can't
they're not taking my feedback if they
do it's it's as a customer not as as an
owner and that's a very different
relationship whereas even if we start
with something that's nowhere near as
good as a discord to begin with we can
we can say hey every time I get a new
link from a new group of people you give
me a new account this is not sustainable
this is not okay this is not user
friendly stop it let me sign in with
Google and Facebook and if we want him
to sign him with Google and Facebook we
could
partly when we start our own technology
cooperative Facebook and Google aren't
as scary as they are right now because
but not 10,000 but a million could
definitely take over Facebook and Google
and I don't sir takeovers the wrong word
a million people could recreate Facebook
into something we can trust and use it
is our version of that with all of the
the tools that are in Facebook and all
the people and if the million people on
it who cares if your family and friends
are on it you can coordinate with those
billion people and then because if
there's already a threshold of usability
it's gonna draw in other people who's
gonna pick to be on Facebook where you
you know that they're selling you
everything you know that your data isn't
safe but they have they have your
friends and family hostage well if they
don't anymore because there's a better
newer version of what Facebook gives us
but we own it together
who's gonna choose to be on Facebook
when they know both of those
simultaneously exist I don't know anyone
who would but with that with that
understanding so with 10,000 people and
$100,000 a weekend basically create an
improvement in any area of life and
because the solution raisings are
designed to create a solution that costs
a hundred thousand dollars to implement
so a food app that helps you grow an
actual garden with the crowdsource
knowledge and the knowledge of expertise
and helps you figure out where to plant
and when to water it when we did what
insects are there and why those those
kind of things is going to you create
that so when you first would create the
collaboration platforms we don't have
anything else or we would buy one of the
existing collaboration platforms that
which for a hundred thousand is a bit of
a stretch but there are tons of what we
called like project management team
management apps out there that are all
$10 a month per person per per team I
don't think any of them are sustainable
and yet all of them probably are
adequate enough to bring teams together
so with the understanding that they're
all all that one of them actually lets
all of them are going to go into
business the only way they succeed is if
Facebook and Google buy them
we can buy them we could actually come
together and be like well if this tool
actually works because ten thousands
just the beginning stage if we had again
a hundred thousand people a million
dollars or a million people and ten
million dollars we could buy a ton of
the apps that already created if they
meet our needs but because they were
designed for a tiny group of people for
profit they probably won't meet our
needs to the same extent as we will we
can facilitate our needs being met if
we're involved in the creation process
and so that is what we could create now
with 10,000 people hundred thousand
dollars is a collaboration platform that
then we know every month we have a
hundred thousand dollars to spend on a
project and yes we have to keep all the
projects going as well so it's a bit of
because of course that's not how it
worked at all but we also are gonna be
recruiting so more and more stick to one
subject 10,000 people paying $100,000
into a pool because they know that we're
co-creating solutions together they know
they get to pick a new solution every
month and they can be as involved in it
as possible if you're not interested in
the food creation app that's fine you're
probably gonna be interested in using it
because you eat so if it helps you eat
for less money and less less resources
put in and you know that and you can see
that this is how much the average person
is saved in that why wouldn't you be
part of it you not necessarily gonna
want to be a part in the creating it and
deciding what the features are because
maybe that's not your passion and and
but there's one on child care and you're
like oh I have ideas for that way so you
can choose which which projects to be
part of but you're paying your ten
dollars every month you know that it's
going to projects in general and
especially in the beginning we're gonna
be starting with the ones that
facilitate the process ie the
collaboration platform and then the ones
are gonna have the biggest impact on the
most of our lives right food clothing
shelter education transportation the the
big categories and then we will be more
focused on the niche ones after we've
solved the bigger issues I mean there's
people all over the world right now
solving dozen
if not hundreds of issues with there's
an app for that but they own it by
themselves they have to go through all
of the roadblocks that every new
technology has to go through do we trust
them who are they do they have longevity
how do we trust them I don't know what
this projects actually gonna do even if
they had the best of intentions in mind
to actually save the world how do I know
that how do I know you're not a Russian
bot it's gonna use my dad and overthrown
by government or something in strange
how and success in the technology sphere
generally means being bought out from
out so amounts of money by Google or
Facebook or if you're not willing to
sell them they just recreate your
technology and out-compete you and
there's of course a few instances for
that doesn't happen but the vast
majority of us find that is what happens
the big players in the industry either
buy you out or they recreate your your
product and none of that is helping us
as individuals having Google and
Facebook be monopolies it's not helping
us have more security over our data it's
not helping us it I mean it's improving
our lives or we wouldn't be using the
tools at all but it's not improving our
lives to the same degree we could be
improving our lives if we owns the
technology together so that we can trust
it so that we can use it because yes if
Google came up with an app that helped
me eat better I would probably use it
but it's not gonna be the same and it's
not going to be interconnected with the
other the other pieces in a way that's
gonna profit me it's gonna be in a way
that profits Google they're in it for
themselves and their shareholders
they're not in it for me so if there's a
decision to be made to make my life
better or to make another dollar they're
gonna pick the one that makes another
dollar unless the one that makes my life
better makes them more than another
dollar
they're in it to make those decisions
for profit and so I i'll buy with thanks
so much better when there's a group of
us doing it it's 15 minutes 15 minutes
30 minutes but this is basically I just
went through a bit of what if a solution
reason is is that we get together and
talk for 15 minutes on what is currently
being done so what I was talking about
was that we are a very individualistic
society you have to solve your problems
by yourself you have to get a job and if
you can't find a job it's too bad like
you are a failure as human being why
wouldn't someone hire you you're not
part of the charismatic 1% you're not
part of the there's many reasons someone
won't hire smiles but if he or not if
we're in it for ourselves if we're only
in it we have to figure out a put food
on our own table and a roof over our own
head then we're in competition with each
other and your neighbor is your enemy
and even if that's just subconscious if
you succeed that's costing me something
is what we currently have in society if
you have an idea you're just you're
supposed to concentrate on how you're
gonna profit from it so that you and
your offspring can have more money so
you can out-compete your neighbors and
your your the other people who could
maybe have ideas that has given us what
we have including our level of ingenuity
and innovation right now but it also
costs us all of the innovation ingenuity
that slips through the cracks all of the
people we don't listen to because
they're not part of that normal business
1% they're not part they don't look like
someone we should listen to they don't
look like someone who has good ideas
they don't look like which is ridiculous
because what does somebody with a good
idea look like you don't anyway so that
is what a bit of what's happening now is
for individualistic and we have to solve
our own issues in the future I would
like us to empower the individual to
solve their own issues without it being
a competitive system where your success
equals somebody else's failure you
getting the best business means that
nine others went out of business and
with them their ingenuity and innovation
because you didn't solve all of the
problems you possibly can't possible
especially if you're in it for profit
but together we can actually solve the
solutions in the most efficient
equitable way that for you to succeed I
get to succeed as well if you can come
up with an innovation that helps you cut
five minutes off of your cooking time
every week and you can give that to
everybody else everybody just cook five
minutes out the cooking time and if
you're the only one coming up with those
things I can see why you would want to
maybe get profit off of it
but that means that everyone has to get
profit and we all have to pay that price
as opposed to right but but you get all
the innovation everyone else puts into
the pool as well so having a parallel
system to our competitive one that is
based on cooperation that doesn't
require people give up their competitive
side that doesn't require people give up
their human nature that wants themselves
to succeed
you can't help individuals not to
succeed for the for the benefit of the
group but if we allow people people's
innovation and individual drive to
benefit the group then its Omni win then
everybody wins cuz every new innovation
is is available to everyone every new
idea is available to everyone and
because it's voluntary it's not top-down
it's not your government or your boss
telling you you have to give this of the
goodness of your heart you're gonna be
ostracized if you don't give eighteen
hours a week to the collective good it
is the the I always want to say the
opposite is it the opposite it is
different than that it is who are you
what do you have to give regardless of
whether or not it's profitable how can
we facilitate you and giving your gifts
to the world what would those tools and
technology look like they didn't that
enabled you to live your best life what
would it look like for technology to
help you eat your best to help you live
your peak health to help you find and
maintain connections and relationships
that help you feel seen and loved and
connected what does it look like what
are the tools you need in order to live
your passion and your purpose and when I
say those things I don't mean them as
overarching most people don't have an
overarching purpose or passion they can
put into a elevator pitch sentence you
might have a project right now and a
project in the future and there you
can't even see how they're connected
they're connected by you everyone's
purpose and genius is to be themselves
is to show up in the world and be
themselves and so in so doing there's
gonna be people who are engineers people
who are doctors people who are artists
and people who are every combination
that exists and that is our greatest
resource is our diversity in our
humanity is that there are 7.5 billion
of us walking around with unique
experiences unique genetics and just
solve any problem there's enough
intelligence and enough data it's just
not organized and if we can organize it
in any way we can create a world that
works for everyone I mean if what
information do you want to have access
to if there's subjects that you love
what do you want that to look like so
you can explore it with other people who
want to geek out in that area of
choosing if you don't like a subject but
you wish you knew it what would it look
like for you to be wanting to use it in
a way that's that's actually useable
instead of you needing to memorize it
use it right the periodic table is a
great example of a piece of information
that you don't need to memorize it in
and of itself if you have it available
hat it contains a lot of information
what does that look like with history
what does that look like with biology
and physics and current events what does
it look like to have the information
accessible to you in a usable
understandable way that you could it was
so you could use it so you could use
history if you're creating a movie right
what would it instead of having to go in
research or the Kapiti articles
what would the visualization what would
with your learning style and your
interests how could we give you access
to history no matter where on the
spectrum you exist no matter where
whether you're extremely interested in
history or not at all interest in
history if you're at learning it
so you mean you come in contact with
anything and you memorize it or it's
really hard for it sticking your
those those are definitely correlated
spectrums but not necessarily you could
be really interesting history and just
really suck picking it up you can also
not at all be interested in it and pick
it up really easily but generally
speaking your interest sticks with what
you actually want to auto compilation
basically once we have ten thousand
people in a hundred thousand dollars we
can save the entire world we can for
ourselves because we can high ten
thousand people that are putting in ten
dollars a month can create all of the
technology we need in order to be able
to succeed and that's the starting point
because of course one hundred thousand
dollars a month isn't gonna be enough to
run a hundred different apps but it'll
be enough to run a few and then if we
have let's say a food app a
transportation app and a I'm gonna say
labor app because it actually starts to
pay for itself it pays for other ones we
have a natural recruiting tool really
the first app that's beyond the
collaboration platform that helps us and
maybe we don't have a collaboration lab
or maybe that's not our first one maybe
we do concentrate our first project on
one that's gonna have more of an impact
on people's lives directly like a
healthcare one or a law refinance one or
a food one but eventually we need a
collaboration one one that we is a
dashboard for the individual to see what
projects they're on what what level
they're involved in right or they just
are they just answering polite questions
or they just watching a group of experts
have our Braille Aegis people who saw
selected as experts people who it's
already are the best we have that itself
selected so if there's we need five
people and five people put up their hand
those are the five people if we need
five people and 500 people put up their
hand how do we decide which ones are the
best that we want to be in a group of
people and maybe because we're working
we're coming up through the process to
work through a process there are
infinite
iterations this looks like it could look
like and probably will look like in the
beginning unless we think of something
outside of the box a normal-type
corporation with the board of directors
but the board of directors can run with
liquid democracy the board of directors
can run like a user cooperative it can I
mean even with the existing what that
looks like there's still multiple
iterations and different things we can
try we can create the technology so we
don't necessarily need a board of
directors
absolutely Schuyler I'll just put this
on the screen because I'm reading I
realize all of yesterday's I had some
kind of a troll in here talking and all
I was doing was reading his periscope
comments I didn't ever put on the screen
that was because they weren't good and
yeah we can absolutely have a private
conversation to do that I mean I'm I
think you're right I think our missions
and our our vision are hugely in
alignment my issue with with teaming up
strong word because I'm all for
collaboration and teaming up is that
anything that can be written on paper
like this is our vision of values I've
done that for myself I don't know if you
have Shilo like what is the sticking
point values that I cannot be involved
with if it's not part of it and what do
I need it to be part of and then even
that like if it's it's like four out of
the five I don't know can we find to the
fifth one I don't know I know what are
they they're transparency or better
democracy or better fun and easy like I
need it to be enjoyable to have the
process and for me it's not necessarily
part of the project itself but it's my
life I have to be able to live on my own
terms and so right now with which I
think would work just fine with the two
horses and more people because that's
part of is if I feel I can't follow the
next thing that my brain comes up with
the next idea the next and or I need to
like run it by a group of people before
I can actually just take the first step
and see is this something valuable then
I feel to restrict
for that idea T and therefore the ideas
don't come up and there isn't that that
energy to enter in debate on whereas if
I can kind of follow the path laid out
before me even though when it's not laid
out before me it's like the next GPS
coordinate as long as I'm following that
it is so intermixed with like the
technology cooperative and what we
create together in the process that I I
have to be able to live my life and I
don't think that us working together
anyway wouldn't restrict that but other
people have absolutely other people like
well this it has to be XY and Z and like
really doesn't and I feel what's the
word hypocritical because I feel like
I'm doing that like it has to be
transparent and democratic and this but
yes if someone hasn't sat down with
their values and said like I don't know
it's not a fascist organization no not
at my alley
like I really do want I don't even know
what the wording of this is and I think
of being alignment with yours is um I
don't like elitism I don't want there to
be a new group so anytime there's like
well we'll get all of the elites
together all of the intellects I'll have
them like mmm there's something about
that that never I want and yet I respect
that
like I don't want fifth graders playing
in the NBA I want the top of the talk
well my kidding but if there is an NBA
you want the top at the top in there but
you want fifth graders to be able to
play basketball I feel like that is the
key to anything that we do is everyone
should be able to be involved in it and
every level and if there is a higher
level someone can play out right they
then there can be differently this is I
guess what I'm saying there could be
different leagues but it but everyone
gets to play everyone gets a basketball
in a court everyone gets to be able to
play just not you don't get to be in the
NBA necessarily right there's only so
much room in the NBA and that type of
everyone and anyone can be involved and
we can have the discussion on what that
looks like if there's already a board of
directors it's already a path we're
following and you're the next person on
you don't get to chicken derail
everything and
cluding me like if my next idea derails
everything I got to figure out what that
looks like and it seems to work and work
together seems to be that it won't
derail it it was more my internal part
that was degree living it's like my
internal part that was like okay you
have to wait between board meetings to
bring up ideas so that you doesn't feel
like you're trampling on other people's
feet like yeah actually I needed to be
able to just run with the idea let the
people know between board meetings like
hey here's what what I was working on
and then let it go in between what is
the word like structured setup things
that I have whatever that word is like I
have this every morning at 8:30 I have
the idea cafe in an hour which I don't
know if anyone showing up for cuz I
wasn't gonna hold the idea cafe this
week and then I decided to hold it on
Who am I and so we'll see if anyone
shows up and wanted to answer Who am I
and I don't know what the conversation
looks like after that but I know that if
the four questions if we're able to come
together and answer them in any way
really in any way then it is an internal
motivation you get something knowing who
you are pays for itself on every level
and seem keep digging you keep figuring
out who you are at a deeper more real
and authentic level it doesn't for me
anyway have anything to do with what
society says someone should look like
because they're generally not in
alignment with each other it's in fact
the more I look like someone different
than that not the better but the more I
know it's mine and not theirs the more I
know it's it's my values and my
uniqueness I'm living by and not trying
to be something that I'm not
anyway the more were able to answer Who
am I the more benefit we have in and of
itself the more we're able to answer who
are my people and find them and
facilitate that process the the better
our lives are and therefore the better
we show up in the world and the more we
can help other people do that process
the more we're able to answer what is my
purpose today in this hour in this
moment
in life in this week what am I currently
doing what's the best next action what's
a adequate next action to take that is
mine to take and then taking it
especially in groups that were connected
to as our individual selves that were
constantly trying to figure out and then
what do we need to be able to live our
lives people to have our purpose be able
to be in our teams and groups to be able
to be our authentic selves what do we
need to be in place and anytime we
answer those four questions at any level
they pay for themselves but I don't yet
know what that looks like especially
during this hour and what I know it's a
conversation because I know my piece of
this is a conversation it's the big
vision then that although it's mine it's
not mine because it's not I know what my
mind comes up with the big vision but
since it can't communicate it it's not
very helpful so my piece is for me at
least of all the big vision that I hold
and communicate it as well as I can in
the moment the thing that I am capable
of in nearly any moment is to show up
and have a conversation and so and that
is what my brain in the universe keep
giving me is so that it is the two merge
like how do we create a technology
cooperative that solves all of human
problems with the individual and with a
conversation good question my brain will
figure it out or other people like my
part is the conversation and then every
other part that is into conversation
needs other people on board and the more
I argue that is my guys the more I'm
like no I just need to be able to figure
out X like communication great check
that box but I also want to be able to
code I also want to be able to edit
video I want to be able to mark it and
have people show up and have it not be
not the arduous and then anytime I try
to do the work that isn't mine to do it
I fall apart doesn't like it falls party
doesn't fall apart at all I fall apart a
little because I'm not accepting myself
for who I am and it's
I'm not a coder and I can't learn to
edit instead of like right but what I
can do is have a conversation I'm just
what I'm wrecking it well that's other
listen University are so important to me
plus I cannot overextend myself either
but feel free having a partner I could
be an amazing that ya know and that is
is that piece of it the overextended
part someone commented on my video is
one of the people from game B about how
what I'm trying to do is very comp I
don't remember the word he is I'm gonna
use arduous even though that was not
what he he had said and it's what I took
it to me I'm like I get that what I'm
trying to do is bigger than what anyone
has tried to do and at the same time so
then it sounds arduous but it's not
because I'm never gonna do it beyond my
capacity I'm never gon I can't push
myself into being something I'm not so
if what I can do is be part of a kind of
a conversation and allow my brain to be
what it currently is then I can't
require anyone do anything but that
right if I'm gonna do it in a way that's
fun and easy for me then everyone has to
do in a way that's fun and easy for them
or they have to be willing to take on
like it has to be enjoyable for them to
take on something that's more arduous
has to be enjoyable for them to take on
something that's more challenging them
but like there's this idea especially in
the world changing community like the
people who protest the people who sign
petitions the people who are involved
and on not-for-profits they're the
burnout rate is so high and so many
people I know who are the most
compassionate amazing people have
chronic illness due to their compassion
myself included and to say that you have
to be something other than who you are
to give your gifts that you have to like
you have to overextend yourself it's
what is required like you have to work
60 hours a week in this not-for-profit
you have to just doesn't work and I've
tapped into the opposite of that and I
don't know if it works for everyone
because not everyone has my conditions
on everyone has to do that but if it
does work why not live in that world
where we all do what's easy and fun for
us
and anything that's left over that truly
isn't easy and fun for anyone okay we'll
figure out some external incentivization
so the work gets done but there's
something in me that keeps proving it
and Simon in me it's in the universe it
keeps proving itself that the right
people show up when I truly allow it
because sometimes I can't even
articulate what those right people are
because even if they articulate and
whatever even the articulation of the
idea put so much on it then it like if I
say I need an admin person and I do I do
need Ben person then it looks like game
a admit right okay I have an admin
degree I have it's like no that's not
right which is gonna come into conflict
because their idea button man isn't it
so my idea minute man isn't it's like
well what of what I'm doing isn't
working that you could fix right well
your video should be editing okay cool
can you get it because then we can we
can add that into it I show up for one
talk and I don't know what was talked
about I wish there was note taking great
can you take notes right like so it's
what's broken about what's currently
happening what would you like to improve
on it's easy and fun for you so it's
just you can figure out that it's broken
right I know these videos these videos
relax but like if I was able to talk for
my heart for 20 minutes and someone else
was able to edit it down to five minutes
they would be a regular amazing YouTube
video and then that we might have more
than 150 subscribers and then we would
have might be able to get to the 10,000
people who are willing to pay 10 bucks a
month and we could actually create the
better world but I don't know what that
looks like is if I give it a job
description and somebody steps into that
job description it's not the same as
what piece of this is yours because this
isn't about me giving my vision and then
people stepping on board with it and I
I'm the like colonel and I have the the
army of people fulfilling my vision even
if that's what people want it to look
like it can't look like that because
then then it's an army than it is one
central person if I die if I'm
assassinated if I got something wrong
then that is her PA permeated into the
world
that's not propagated it copies itself
in the world and if we design things
from the bottom if it involves if you're
allowed to bring yourself and your
ingenuity and find the place that works
for you and what did those tools look
like because it doesn't we're not going
to find five Board of Directors are
going to be perfectly aligned with
person I don't think anything may be
theater as those works that way but like
with perfectly aligned personality and
skills and challenges but this is all we
need
it's nor can we put it into a job
description right because then if one
person leaves we're like oh we need a
new Jubilee we need somebody who can
think big picture and have a
conversation and that's it like oh no
they can do other things we don't need
that
that happy and people come on board as
they feel the need to come on board like
yes this is something that resonates
with me and and I've had a few people
contact me like what do you need how can
I help like I don't know what can you do
what is yours to do and how to do that
process when I can't do the event
it up with emails do mean that is too
arduous that it's not fun and easy for
me I do it enough that it's it's like
all right but not really sometimes I'll
go a week without checking my email be
like whoops oops I forgot to respond to
you especially then the collaborative
democracy level and or I'm like I don't
know what to respond to you so I forget
to respond that's not very businesslike
but it's authentic it's like this is how
people react people with with I don't
know I think it's a word at the moment
executive functioning issues okay and
communication issues and social anxiety
and all these things is like it costs me
too many spoons to respond to an email
that I can't think of how to respond to
it so I don't and then I forget about it
it doesn't get responded to which is not
very professional but if I can own that
and so he'll this is able to possibly
take on that role then great and I get
that this process this newer part it's
beginning part of this process is very
large
process which means I have to make it
even more fun and easy for me that it
has to be enjoyable in and of itself
even if no one ever joined me it has to
be enjoyable and yet I've already there
already are people joining me right like
Shiloh and Bentley and Adriel and
everyone who has their own vision of
what together tech is their own vision
of what it looks like to come together
and create a world that works for
everyone
and yet they mesh well together you
don't need like and that is where being
the central authority means you have to
chew you have to listen to my authority
you have to how much am I willing to
hear dissension to my ideas and it
shouldn't be reliance on that even
though I'm pretty good at hearing
dissensions my ideas it shouldn't be
reliant on one weapon person or one
groups one tiny groups ideas it's about
what is your vision of the world and as
long as it's not fascist as long as it's
not and this is it it's hard because
we're all little fascist a little bit
well if everyone just did X we'd all be
better off well anyone anytime we're
like everyone on to do X it becomes
fascism which we're currently seen under
our under our pandemic quarantine world
right that although everybody should be
staying inside and socially distancing
putting it under log giving people fines
giving people jail time has a lot of
pushback because the people like your
fashion is related our governments take
over our lives and look what's happening
and then they're on the street protest
and then they get arrested and it proves
itself to them and it's like there has
to be especially in these overarching I
don't know what the solutions that is
because my solution is like right we
have to keep asking people who aren't
maintaining social distancing why and
help them fix the reason why as opposed
to giving them penalization for and not
listening to them as to why they're not
ok with doing it but because that's all
we can do I can get I do get angry
people who are in social distancing and
he's like why just put them in jail
given their own islands do something but
that's that's my fascist part right like
that's like
one needs to do this or the world falls
apart and so if we need everyone to give
up their car and ride a bike we need
everyone to go vegan it's not a solution
it's not voluntary we can ride a bike we
can ask other people what would you
require for them to write if I can give
up in a car or use their car less we
could ask people how what would make
them go vegan or what would make the
meat more vegan but we can't dictate
that this is how you have to live your
life in order to be part of it unless
you're literally a vegan group right
then you probably need to be be gonna be
part of it and so that piece of it like
anyone can come on board bring their
ingenuity in themselves give their gifts
and you cannot impose your view on
anybody else you can offer it but you
can't impose it right I can't I can't go
out and kidnap 10,000 people and demand
they've had $10 a month it has to be
something that's in it for them it has
to be a good enough offer that it
perpetrates it's whatever that p-word is
itself propagates propagates itself into
the world right that it goes viral the
old-school good version of viral that's
not true it's like old school I'm pretty
sure viruses are old school viruses
they've been around since the dawn of
time earlier than bacteria probably but
the viral you know to be what we what we
knew viral to mean six months ago goes
of that kind of viral not everyone has
to hide away from it because it's really
gone pandemic viral and so yeah
absolutely
let's try let's check and I'm down with
it being a private conversation although
I like all of my conversations to be
recorded and live which for new random
strangers might be I'm not busy enough
yet for me to make that but there was
someone I talked to yesterday and I
didn't know it was gonna be posted he
said yes to it so it will be posted but
there was something about when cuz
that's my old my old way when I first
came into game B I had a lot of
interviews and a lot of conversations
with people and I always leave it up to
them whether we publish it or not
because it helps them show up
differently but
then there's also the that was an hour
of my time and now we can't publish it
and I want to be fully transparent that
like if someone's meeting with me here
here's all the conversations up and
having so there's something about like
well if you want to have a conversation
with me it has to be public and
available to everyone but I'm not there
yet and I'm not there for people that I
like there are people with a ton of
people with world-changing ideas that
aren't comfortable on camera aren't
comfortable even on voice chat and I'm
not comfortable on text so it means we
are not compatible like I can't have a
conversation with those people because
I'm not going to have a conversation
through it by a reading and then typing
and reading and typing and they're not
gonna have a conversation on video or
voice so like we are not compatible but
luckily they'll be people they talk to
and then people I talk to and those
circles will overlap yes so but you know
words it's up so tomorrow is the
solution raising on resiliency
efficiency and fragility and we'll be
hosting it tomorrow here at 8:30 in the
morning
yes cific standard time or pacific PDT
Daylight Time Pacific Daylight Time um
yeah that's cool that's what it's also
totally down but it's just yeah the
iteration of there are ton of people I'm
like after all the conversation like
wait if I don't really believe in your
idea I believe in your shadow I think
you're you're I think we have a lot in
common
um even if I don't fully understand your
idea I could I could see that the
parallel like yeah I got I know I know
how to understand the world but there's
other people who I read their idea and
I'm like this is not a solution and I
maybe if you're willing to have a
conversation about it on camera I'm
still willing to have a conversation
because I'm gonna learn from it and grow
and other people will learn from it and
grow but if like I can't have one of the
people falls under this umbrella I can't
have a conversation with them because
they won't have a conversation I'm video
voice I don't like their idea in no way
think it's a solution to anything I
think they're wasting their time but
it's like I can't and they just
constantly put it into everything
they're just constantly like
this is a solution oh yeah that's like
this solution I'm like I'm constantly
talking technology cooperative it's a
solution to everything but it actually
is a solution everything tap it help
with that if we owned the tacit even
more powerful and less risky so why not
it literally solves everything
whereas changing prices doesn't it has
if you don't understand economics it has
a whole other implication but wasn't
pointed that I don't want to be
belittling other people's ideas
I guess just if I can if I can't play
with
yeah it's it just and then the person
also every time I do point it's like
well you're just not open to new ideas
and like I'm extremely open to new ideas
I just there's another one I he emailed
me and I don't his his solution is that
Bill Gates should be Prince president or
we should let the people decide if Bill
Gates president and I in no way want
Bill Gates to be President but when I
think Bill Gates make a better president
and Trump hands down and so if it's his
passion project I'm willing to have a
conversation to help push it I'm not
willing to help push the project for him
I'm going to have a conversation or
whatever he could get out of it to purge
the project forward because I can see
that he's passionate about that and if
Bill Gates was president okay like it
was like all right well it's if it's
between Biden and Bill I do I did pick
Bill I do but I also don't want Bill
Gates to be I don't like though like I
like Bill Gates to human being what he's
interviewed I don't like billionaire
philanthropy pay your freakin taxes stop
thinking that you know how to save the
world with your money that you ported I
mean that's just I think we could do
more with the million dollars I think
giving Microsoft to the people could be
more that we could do with the billion
dollars how about we decide but you open
source that vaccine information so that
we can see how safe and effective they
are there's a lot of things that I would
do what are Bill Gates but I wouldn't do
them if I was Bill Gates because it
might be Bill Gates and I wouldn't have
passed a billion dollars me is never
masking a billion dollars even want to
give me money I'm like that's gonna ruin
everything
I just want to give my gifts to the
world and I'll deal with all of that
myself I am dealing with it but I'm just
running on maybe I just need to stay on
these for a whole hour or is it somebody
else odd with me but like I said
tomorrow we're doing the solution
raising if you would like to join in I
don't post the links the day of because
the point of the solution raising is you
are supposed to be there for the full
hours to participate and all three parts
of the conversation so people can't like
pop it and pop out but if you would like
to participate in that
raising then DME on twitter at crowded
democracy or on Facebook but if we're
not friends it's gonna be a little hard
or you can comment I with you something
that that I can get a hold of you with
without you know while working with
YouTube's algorithm don't put in the
dot-com put in like the dot like the
word dot and whatever tell me how to get
in contact with you if you want to
participate in the solution raising and
we'll figure it out otherwise I'm gonna
say goodbye and I cuz I have a good idea
Cafe at ten which is in less than an
hour and I'm gonna go and meditate for
ten twenty minutes and then I will be on
the idea Cafe channel in 10 a.m. for the
idea Cafe if someone shows up for it and
if not then I will not be going live
because I don't go live by myself on the
idea cafe but I will if there is at
least one person who shows up we will be
talking about Who am I I will see you
all tomorrow for the socialising
Thursday I'm off because I'm going to be
going grocery shopping and I can't get
back in time just to go live at 8:30 in
the morning and then Friday I'm going to
be doing coaching again which means
anyone who wants to be coached I'm going
to figure out either the relationship
with self relationship with others or
purpose in life tool is that is what I
want to be focused on I want to figure
out how to do that in a group of people
who are interested so that they all can
figure out who we are and realizing I
had this year the whole time it didn't
actually put it up if you wanted to join
in
oh no I had it here I just didn't do
this I just didn't do this that's why
I'm a periscope filters from the person
I guess they don't know I'm the person
who owns the periscope account because
you know just broadcasting through yards
but anyway I put it up here and it
didn't actually put it up on the screen
for people to follow that's alright
we'll figure it out for Friday
cuz I'm Friday like I said we're gonna
to be doing like coaching Oh Thursday
not on and tomorrow is solution raising
and then Saturday is my usual update for
20 minutes before doing our project
roundtable on you together touch Channel
and so I will see you all tomorrow to
raise solutions for resiliency fragility
and efficiency and I hope some of you
can train okay bye